Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Byron, George Gordon Noël Byron, 6th baron., 1788-1824; 7 envelopes (Box 2, Item 1)
    - "Muse of the many-twinkling feet! Whose charms" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - Napoleon's Farewell. "Farewell to the Land where the gloom of my Glory" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - On the Star of 'The Legion of Honour'. "Star of the brave! - whose beam hath shed" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - On This Day I Complete My Thirty Sixth Year. "'Tis time this heart should be unmoved" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - Parisina. "With many a lingering look they leave" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - The Prisoner of Chillon. (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - "Remind me not, remind me not" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - "Roll on, thou deep and dark blue Ocean - roll!" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - She Walks In Beauty. "She walks in beauty, like the night" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - The Siege of Corinth. "Darkly, sternly, and all alone" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - The Spell Is Broke, The Charm Is Flown! "The spell is broke, the charm is flown!" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Stanzas To Augusta. "Thought the day of my destiny's over" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Stanzas For Music. "There's not a joy the world can give like that it takes away" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Sublime Tobacco. "Sublime tobacco! Which from east to west" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - "There was a sound of revelry by night" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - To Inez. "Nay, smile not at my sullen brow;" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - "To sit on rocks, to muse o'er flood and fell" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - To Thomas Moore. "My boat is on the shore" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Translation of the Famous Greek War Song. "Sons of the Greeks, arise!" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 7)
    - Well! Thou Art Happy. "Well! thou art happy, and I feel" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 7)
    - When We Two Parted. "When we two parted" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 7)
  - Calverley, Charles Stuart., 1831-1884; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Changed, "I know not why my soul is rack'd:" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Forever, "Forever; 'tis a single word!" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Morning, "'Tis the hour when white-horsed Day" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - My Cherry Stones, "My cherry stones, I prize them" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Beer, "In those old days which poets say were golden-" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Charades I, "She stood at Greenwich, motionless amid" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Ode to Tobacco, "Thou who, when fears attack" (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Calverley, original poem unidentified (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Campbell, Thomas., 1777-1844; 5 envelopes (Box 2, Item 3)
    - Battle of the Baltic, "Of Nelson and the North" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 1)
    - Exile of Erin, "There came to the beach a poor Exile of Erin-" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 1)
    - Hohenlinden, "On Linden, when the sun was low" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 2)
    - The Last Man. "All worldly shapes shall melt in gloom" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 2)
    - Lochiel's Warning. "Lochiel, Lochiel! Beware of the day" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - Lord Ullin's Daughter, "A chieftain to the Highlands bound" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - The Maid's Remonstrance. "Never wedding, ever wooing" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - The Pleasures of Hope. "At Summer eve, when Heav'n's aerial bow" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - The Soldier's Dream, "Our bugles sang truce; for the night-cloud had lower'd" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - Song of Hybrias the Cretan. "My wealth's a burley spear and brand" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 3)
    - Ye Mariners of England, "Ye mariners of England" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 4)
    - Ye mariners of England, "Ye mariners of England," ... continued (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 5)
    - Gertrude of Wyoming. Part III. "O love! In such a wilderness as this" (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 5)
    - Parodies in the style of Campbell, original poem unidentified (Box 2, Item 3, Envelope 5)
  - The Campbells Are Comin'. "The Campbells are comin', Oho, Oho,", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 4)
  - Campion, Thomas., 1567-1620; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 5)
    - "The man of life upright" (Box 2, Item 5)
  - Canning, George [and George Ellis, ], 1770-1827; 1753-1815; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 6)
    - Song by Rogero, "Whene'er with haggard eyes I view" (Box 2, Item 6)
  - Carey, Henry., 1665-1743; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 7)
    - God Save the King, "God save our gracious King!" (Box 2, Item 7)
    - Sally in Our Alley. "Of all the girls that are so smart" (Box 2, Item 7)
  - Carlyle, Joseph Dacre., 1759-1804; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item Item)
    - On the Battle of Sabla, "Sabla, thou saw'st th'exulting foe" (Box 2, Item Item)
  - Carman, Bliss., 1861-1929; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 9)
    - Hack and Hew, "Hack and Hew were the sons of God" (Box 2, Item 9)
    - Spring Song, "Make me over, Mother April" (Box 2, Item 9)
  - Cartwright, William., 1611-1643; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 10)
    - Celia Upon Her Sparrow. "Tell me not of joy: there's none" (Box 2, Item 10)
  - Cary, Alice., 1820-1871; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 11)
    - Dying Hymn. "Earth, with its dark and dreadful ills" (Box 2, Item 11)
  - Cawein, Madison Julius., 1865-1914; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 12)
    - Parodies in the style of Cawein, original poem unidentified (Box 2, Item 12)
  - Charlie is My Darling. "Twas on a Monday morning", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 13)
    - Charlie is My Darling. "'Twas a Monday morning'" (Box 2, Item 13)
  - Chaucer, Geoffrey., ca. 1340-1400; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 14)
    - The Canterbury Tales, various tales. (Box 2, Item 14)
  - Cherry, Andrew, 1762-1812., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 15)
    - The Bay of Biscay O! "Loud roared the dreadful thunder!" (Box 2, Item 15)
    - Tom Moody. "You all knew Tom Moody, the whipper-in, well;" (Box 2, Item 15)
  - Chesterton, Gilbert Keith, 1874-1936., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 16)
    - Parodies in the style of Chesterton, original poem unidentified (Box 2, Item 16)
  - Chevy Chace. "God prosper long our noble king,", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 17)
  - Chit Chat. "Pretty little damsels, how they chat,", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 18)
  - Chorley, Henry Forthergill, 1808-1872., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 19)
    - The Brave Old Oak. "A song to the oak, the brave old oak" (Box 2, Item 19)
  - Cibber, Colley, 1671-1857., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 20)
    - Birthday Ode, "Let there be light!" (Box 2, Item 20)
    - Ode for his Majesty's Birthday. "Great patriot prince, of race sublime!" (Box 2, Item 20)
    - Ode on New Year's Day, 1731. "Once more the ever circling Sun" (Box 2, Item 20)
    - Parodies in the style of Cibber, original poem unidentified (Box 2, Item 20)
  - Claribel., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 21)
    - "I cannot sing the old songs" (Box 2, Item 21)
    - Won't You Tell Me Why, Robin? "You are not what you were, Robin;" (Box 2, Item 21)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne., 1835-1910; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 22)
    - Punch, Brothers, Punch. "Conductors when you receive a fare" (Box 2, Item 22)
  - Clough, Arthur Hugh., 1819-1861; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 23)
    - Say Not the Struggle Naught Availeth. "Say not the struggle naught availeth" (Box 2, Item 23)
    - Parodies in the style of Clough original poem unidentified. (Box 2, Item 23)
  - Coleridge Hartley., 1796-1849; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 24)
    - "She is not fair to outward view" (Box 2, Item 24)
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor., 1772-1834; 3 envelopes (Box 2, Item 25)
    - The Ancient Mariner. "It is an ancient Mariner" (Box 2, Item 25, Envelope 1)
    - Christabel. "'Tis the middle of the night by the castle clock" (Box 2, Item 25, Envelope 2)
    - "From his brimstone bed at break of day" (Box 2, Item 25, Envelope 2)
    - Kubla Khan. "In Xanada did Kubla Khan" (Box 2, Item 25, Envelope 3)
    - Love. "All thoughts, all passions, all delights" (Box 2, Item 25, Envelope 3)
  - Coleridge, Sara (Coleridge)., 1802-1852; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 26)
    - The Garden Year. "January brings the snow" (Box 2, Item 26)
  - Coleridge, Lamb, and Lloyd., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 27)
    - Parodies in the style of Coleridge, Lamb, and Lloyd, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 27)
  - Collins, Mortimer., 1827-1876; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 28)
    - Ad Chloen, M.A. "Lady, very fair are you" (Box 2, Item 28)
  - Collins, William., 1721-1759; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 29)
    - How Sleep the Brave. "How sleep the Brave who sink the rest" (Box 2, Item 29)
    - The Passions. "When Music, heavenly Maid, was young" (Box 2, Item 29)
  - Colman, George (the younger)., 1762-1836; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 30)
    - "Mynheer Vandunck, tho' he never was drunk" (Box 2, Item 30)
    - Unfortunate Miss Bailey. "A captain bold in Halifax, that dwelt in country quarters" (Box 2, Item 30)
  - Comin' Through the Rye. "Gin a body meet a body", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 31)
  - Cook, Eliza., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 32)
    - The Old Armchair. "I love it, I love it! And who shall dare" (Box 2, Item 32)
  - Cowley, Abraham., 1618-1667; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 33)
    - Clad All in White. "Fairest thing that shines below" (Box 2, Item 33)
    - Fill the Bowl With Rosy Wine. "Fill the bowl with rosy wine" (Box 2, Item 33)
    - Hymn-To Light. "First-born of chaos, who so fair didst come" (Box 2, Item 33)
  - Cowper, William, 1731-1800., 2 envelopes (Box 2, Item 34)
    - Boadicea. "When the British warrior queen" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - The Jackdaw. "There is a bird who, by his coat" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - John Gilpin. "John Gilpin was a citizen" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - The Negro's Complaint. "Forced from home, and all its pleasures" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - On the Loss of the Royal George. "Toll for the brave,--" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - The Poplar Field. "The poplars are felled; farewell to the shade" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - Report of an Adjudged Case. Not to be Found in any of the Books. "Between Nose and Eyes a strange contest arose,--" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - The Rose. "The rose had been washed, just washed in a shower" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - To Mary. "The twentieth year is well-nigh past" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
    - Verses: Supposed to be Written By Alexander Selkirk During His Solitary Abode in the Island of Juan Fernandez. "I am monarch of all I survey;" (Box 2, Item 34, Envelope 1)
  - Crabbe, George., 1754-1832; 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 35)
    - Parodies in the style of Crabbe, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 35)
  - Craik, Mrs. Dinah Maria (Mulock) 1826-1887., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 36)
    - Too Late. "Could ye come back to me, Douglas, Douglas" (Box 2, Item 36)
  - Crashaw, R., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 37)
    - Wishes for the Supposed Mistress. "Whoe'er she be" (Box 2, Item 37)
  - Crawford, Mrs., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 38)
    - Kathleen Mavourneen. "Kathleen Mavourneen! The gray dawn is breaking" (Box 2, Item 38)
  - Cruscans, Della., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 39)
    - Parodies in the style of the Della Cruscans, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 39)
  - Cullen, C.P., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 40)
    - In Praise of Boys. "Thank God for boys!" (Box 2, Item 40)
  - Cunningham, Allan. 1784-18--, 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 41)
    - A Sea Song. "A wet sheet and a flowing sea-" (Box 2, Item 41)
    - Parodies in the style of Cullen, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 41)
  - Daly, Thomas Augustine, 1871-., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 42)
    - Mona Machree. (Box 2, Item 42)
  - Darley, George, 1795-1846., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 43)
    - I've Been Roaming, I've Been Roaming. (Box 2, Item 43)
  - Darwin, Erasmus, 1731-1802., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 44)
    - Eliza, "Now stood Eliza on the wood-crowned height" (Box 2, Item 44)
    - The Loves Of The Triangle, "The gay Daffodilly, an amorous blade" (Box 2, Item 44)
  - Davidson, John, 1857-1909., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 45)
    - Parodies in the style of Davidson, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 45)
  - Davies, William Henry, 1871-1940., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 46)
    - Leisure, "What is this life if, full of car" (Box 2, Item 46)
    - Parodies in the style of Davies, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 46)
  - Death and the Lady. "Fair lady, lay your costly robes aside,", 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 47)
  - de la Mare, Walter John, 1873-1956., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 48)
    - Parodies in the style of de la Mare, original poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 48)
  - Denham, Sir John, 1615-1699., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 49)
    - Martial Epigram, "Pr'y thee die and set me free" (Box 2, Item 49)
  - Dibdin, Charles, 1745-1814., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 50)
    - Poor Jack, "Stars trembling o'er us and sunset before us" (Box 2, Item 50)
    - The Sailor's Journal, "'Twas post meridian, half-past four" (Box 2, Item 50)
    - Tom Bowling, "Here, a sheer hulk, lies poor Tom Bowling" (Box 2, Item 50)
  - Dibbin, Charles, 1768-1833., 2 envelopes (Box 2, Item 51)
    - The High-Mettled Racer, "See, the course throng'd with gazers, the sports are begun" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 1)
    - The Jolly Young Waterman, "And did you ne'er hear a jolly young waterman" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 1)
    - The Last Shilling, "As pensive one night in my garret I sate" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 2)
    - Tom Tough, "My name d'ye see's Tom Tough, I've seed a little service" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 2)
    - "Then farewell, my trim-built wherry!" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 2)
    - Wapping Old Stairs, "Your Molly has never been false, she declares" (Box 2, Item 51, Envelope 2)
  - Dibbin, Thomas, 1771-1841., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 52)
    - All's Well, "Deserted by the waning moon" (Box 2, Item 52)
    - May We Never Want A Friend, Nor A Bottle To Give Him, "Since the first dawn of reason that beam'd on my mind" (Box 2, Item 52)
    - The Tight Little Island, "Daddy Neptune one day to freedom did say" (Box 2, Item 52)
  - Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 53)
    - The Ivy Green, "Oh, a dainty plant is the Ivy green" (Box 2, Item 53)
    - Ode To An Expiring Frong, "Can I view thee panting, lying" (Box 2, Item 53)
    - "Nicholas Nickleby" (Box 2, Item 53)
    - Parodies in the style of Dickens, source poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 53)
  - Doane, George Washington, 1799-1859., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 54)
    - The Lessons Of The Birds, "What is that mother? The lark my child!" (Box 2, Item 54)
  - Dobell, Sidney, 1824-1874., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 55)
    - The Ballad Of Keith Ravelston, "The murmur of the mourning ghost" (Box 2, Item 55)
    - How's My Boy! "Ho, sailor of the sea!" (Box 2, Item 55)
  - Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 56)
    - An April Pastoral, "He: Whither away, fair Neat-herdess!" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - The Ballad of Prose And Rhyme, "When the ways are heavy with mire and rut" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - A Ballad To Queen Elizabeth, "King Philip had vanted his claims;" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - "Chicken-skin, delicate, white" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - "Farewell, Renown!," "Farewell, renown! Too fleeting flower" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - A Gentleman Of The Old School, "He lived in the past Georgian day" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - In Town, "Toiling in Town now is 'horrid'" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - A Kiss, "Rose kissed me today." (Box 2, Item 56)
    - The Ladies of St. James's," "The ladies of St. James's" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - Mary, Mary, "Because you were, Marie, Marie" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - The Prodigals, "Princes! -and you most valorous" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - A Song of Four Seasons, "When Spring comes laughing" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - "Too hard it is to sing" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - Tu Quoque, "If I were you, when ladies at the play, sir" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - Urceus Exit, "I intended an Ode" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - The Wanderer, "Love comes back to his vacant dwelling, --" (Box 2, Item 56)
    - Parodies in the style of Dobson, source poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 56)
  - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 57)
    - Jabberwocky. "'Twas brillig, and the slithy toves" (Box 2, Item 57)
  - Doubt., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 58)
    - "The waves are breaking on the beach," Anonymous. (Box 2, Item 58)
  - Douglas, Clarence., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 59)
    - Man and Nature. "How grad to stand upon the virgin plain" (Box 2, Item 59)
  - Douglas, William Scott, 1815-1883., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 60)
    - Annie Laurie. "Maxwellton braes are bonnie" (Box 2, Item 60)
  - Dowland, John., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 61)
    - Sleep. "Weep ye no more, dad fountains!" (Box 2, Item 61)
  - Dowson, Ernest Christopher, 1869-1900., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 62)
    - Non Sum Qualis Eram Bonae Sub Regno Cynarae. "Last night, ah, yesternight, betwixt her lips and mine" (Box 2, Item 62)
  - Doyle, Sir Arthur Conan, 1859-1930., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 63)
    - A Rover Chantey. "A trader sailed from Stepney town-" (Box 2, Item 63)
  - Drayton, Michael, 1563-1631., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 64)
    - The Ballad of Agincourt. "Fair stood the wind for France" (Box 2, Item 64)
  - Drinkwater, John, 1862-1937., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 65)
    - Parodies in the style of Drinkwater, source poems unidentified. (Box 2, Item 65)
  - Drummond, William Hamilton, 1778-1865., 1 envelope (Box 2, Item 66)
    - "Doth then the world go thus, doth all thus more?" (Box 2, Item 66)
    - Wreck of the "Julie Plante". "On wan dark night on Lac St. Pierre" (Box 2, Item 66)
  - Dryden, John, 1631-1700., 3 envelopes (Box 3, Item 1)
    - Ah, How Sweet It Is To Love! "Ah, how sweet it is to love!" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - Alexander's Feast; Or, The Power Of Music. "'Twas at the royal feast for Persia won" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - "As some fair tulip, by a storm opprest" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - Farewell, Fair Armida. "Farewell, fair Armida, my joy and my grief!" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - From 'Cymon and Iphigenia'. "In that sweet isle where Venus keeps her court" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - Grand Chorus. "At last divine Cecelia came" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - "I feed a flame within, which so torments me" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - "A milk-white hind, immortal and unchang'd" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - On Milton. "Three Poets, in three distant ages born" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - On Milton. "Three Poets, in three distant ages born," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - "So, two kind turtles, when a storm is nigh" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - Song for St. Cecilia's Day, 1687. "From harmony, from heavenly Harmony" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - Who dares interrupt my private walk?" (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - Parodies in the style of Dryden, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 1, Envelope 3)
  - Dufferin, Lady (Dufferin and Clandeboye, Helen Selina (sheridan) Blackwood, 4th baroness of, 1807-1867), 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 2)
    - Lament of the Irish Emigrant. "I'm sittin' on the stile, Mary" (Box 3, Item 2)
  - The Dutchman's Little Dog., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 3)
    - The Dutchman's Lee-tle Dog. "Oh where, oh where ish mine leetle dog gone." (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Duthie, William., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 4)
    - Men of Harlech. "Men of Harlech! in the hollow" (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Dwight, John Sullivan, 1813-1893., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 5)
    - The Landlady's Daughter. "Three students were travelling over the Rhine;" (Box 3, Item 5)
  - Dyer., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 6)
    - Down Among the Dead Men. "Here's health to the Queen, and a lasting peace" (Box 3, Item 6)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns, 1888-1965., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 7)
    - Parodies in the style of Eliot, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 7)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 8)
    - Brahma. "If the red slayer think he slays" (Box 3, Item 8)
    - Parodies in the style of Emerson, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 8)
  - English, Thomas Dunn, 1819-1902., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 9)
    - Ben Bolt. "Don't you remember sweet Alice, Ben Bolt,--" (Box 3, Item 9)
  - Erskine, William, 1773-1852., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 10)
    - say not Cynthia. "O say not Cynthia, maid divine!" (Box 3, Item 10)
  - Everett, Edward, 1794-1865., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 11)
    - Parodies in the style of Everett, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 11)
  - Fair Helen., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 12)
    - "I wish I were where Helen lies;" (Box 3, Item 12)
  - Fanshawe, Catherine Maria, 1765-1834., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 13)
    - Enigma on the letter H. "'Twas whispered in heaven, 'twas muttered in hell" (Box 3, Item 13)
  - Far Away., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 14)
    - "Where is now the merry party" (Box 3, Item 14)
  - Fargus, Frederick John, 1847-1885., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 15)
    - Some Day. "I know not when the day shall be" (Box 3, Item 15)
  - Fawkes, Francis, 1720-1777., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 16)
    - The Brown Jug. "Dear Tom, this brown jug that now foams with mild ale" (Box 3, Item 16)
  - Field, Eugene, 1850-1895., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 17)
    - Little Boy Blue. "The little toy dog is covered with dust" (Box 3, Item 17)
    - Wynken, Blynken, and Nod. "Wynken, Blynken, and Nod one night" (Box 3, Item 17)
  - Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 18)
    - O, the Roast Beef of Old England! "When mighty roast beef was an Englishman's food" (Box 3, Item 18)
    - Hunting Song. "The dusty night rides down the sky" (Box 3, Item 18)
  - Fields, James Thomas, 1816-1881., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 19)
    - The Tempest. "We were crowded in the cabin" (Box 3, Item 19)
  - The Fine Old English Gentleman., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 20)
    - "I'll sing you a good old song" (Box 3, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - The Fine Old English Gentleman. "I'll sing you a good old song," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 20, Envelope 2)
  - Fitzgerald, Edward, 1809-1833., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 21)
    - Omar Khayyam (Box 3, Item 21, Envelope 1)
    - Omar Khayyam (cont.) (Box 3, Item 21, Envelope 2)
  - Fitzgerald, William Thomas, 1759?-1829., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 22)
    - Parodies in the style of Fitzgerald, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 22)
  - Flecknoe., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 23)
    - "Offspring of a heavenly kind" (Box 3, Item 23)
  - Ford, John, 1586-ca.1640., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 24)
    - "Fly hence shadows that do keep" (Box 3, Item 24)
  - Forgive, Blest Shade., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 25)
    - "Forgive, blest shade, the tributary tear" (Box 3, Item 25)
  - Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 26)
    - The Old Folks at Home. "Why down upon de Suwanee Ribber" (Box 3, Item 26)
  - From Oberon, in Fairy Land., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 27)
    - "From Oberon, in fairy land" (Box 3, Item 27)
  - Garrick, David, 1717-1779., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 28)
    - Hearts of Oak. "Come, cheer up, my lads! 'tis to glory we steer" (Box 3, Item 28)
  - Gay, John, 1685-1732., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 29)
    - Black-eyed Susan. "All in the Downs the fleet was moored" (Box 3, Item 29)
    - "How happy could I be with either" (Box 3, Item 29)
    - "Life is a jest, and all things show it;" (Box 3, Item 29)
    - My Lodging is on the Cold Ground. "My lodging is on the cold ground" (Box 3, Item 29)
  - Gentle Zitella., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 30)
    - "Jolly old fellow, I have heard say" (Box 3, Item 30)
  - Gibbons, James Sloane., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 31)
    - "We are coming, Father Abraham, three hundred thousand more" (Box 3, Item 31)
  - Gibson, Wilfrid Wilson, 1878-., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 32)
    - Parodies in the style of Gibson, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 32)
  - Gilbert, William Schwenck, 1838-1911., 5 envelopes (Box 3, Item 33)